<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.konversation.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <developer id="org.kde">
    <name translate="no">KDE</name>
  </developer>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.kde.konversation.desktop</launchable>
  <name>Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="ar">محادثك</name>
  <name xml:lang="ast">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="bg">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="da">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="el">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="eo">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="et">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="eu">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="he">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="hu">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="ia">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="ie">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="ka">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="lv">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="nn">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="sa">संवादः</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr">Конверзација</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr-Latn">Konverzacija</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr-ijekavian">Конверзација</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr-ijekavianlatin">Konverzacija</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">Konversation</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">Konversation</name>
  <summary>IRC client</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ar">عميل آي‌آرسي</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bg">IRC клиент</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Client d'IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Client d'IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Klient IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="da">IRC-klient</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">IRC-Programm</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="el">Εφαρμογή IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">IRC client</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eo">IRC-kliento</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Cliente de IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="et">IRC klient</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eu">IRC bezeroa</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">IRC-asiakas</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Client IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Cliente de IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="he">לקוח IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hu">IRC kliens</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ia">Cliente IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Klien IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ie">Cliente de IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Client IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ka">IRC კლიენტი</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">IRC 클라이언트</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="lv">IRC klients</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">IRC-client</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nn">IRC-klient</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Klient IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Cliente de IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Cliente IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Клиент IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sa">IRC ग्राहक</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">IRC klient</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Odjemalec za IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr">ИРЦ клијент</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr-Latn">IRC klijent</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr-ijekavian">ИРЦ клијент</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr-ijekavianlatin">IRC klijent</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">IRC-klient</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">IRC istemcisi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Клієнт IRC</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-CN">IRC 客户端</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-TW">IRC 用戶端程式</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Konversation is a user-friendly Internet Relay Chat (IRC) client by KDE.
      It provides easy access to standard IRC networks such as Libera,
      where the KDE IRC channels can be found.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">محادثك هو عميل دردشة عبر الإنترنت سهلة الاستخدام (IRC) بواسطة كِيدِي. يوفر سهولة الوصول إلى شبكات IRC القياسية مثل Libera، حيث يمكن العثور على قنوات كِيدِي IRC.</p>
    <p xml:lang="bg">Konversation е удобен за потребителя Internet Relay Chat (IRC) клиент от KDE. Осигурява лесен достъп до стандартни IRC мрежи като Libera, където могат да бъдат намерени IRC каналите на KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El Konversation és un client fàcil d'emprar de l'Internet Relay Chat (IRC), creat per la comunitat KDE. Proporciona un accés senzill a les xarxes IRC estàndards, com Libera, a on es poden trobar els canals IRC de KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Konversation és un client fàcil d'emprar d'Internet Relay Chat (IRC), creat per la comunitat KDE. Proporciona un accés senzill a les xarxes IRC estàndards, com Libera, a on es troben els canals IRC de KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Konversation ist ein benutzerfreundliches Internet-Relay-Chat (IRC)-Programm von KDE. Es bietet einen einfachen Zugang zu Standard-IRC-Netzwerken wie Libera, wo die KDE-IRC-Kanäle zu finden sind.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Το Konversation είναι μια φιλική στον χρήστη εφαρμογή-πελάτης για την προώθηση συνομιλίας στο Διαδίκτυο (Internet Relay Chat, IRC) από το KDE. Παρέχει εύκολη πρόσβαση σε τυπικά IRC δίκτυα όπως το Libera, όπου μπορείτε να βρείτε τους διαύλους IRC του KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Konversation is a user-friendly Internet Relay Chat (IRC) client by KDE. It provides easy access to standard IRC networks such as Libera, where the KDE IRC channels can be found.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Konversation estas facile uzebla Interreta Relajsa Babilejo (IRC) kliento de KDE. Ĝi disponigas facilan aliron al normaj IRC-retoj kiel Libera, kie la KDE IRC-kanaloj troveblas.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Konversation es un cliente IRC (Internet Relay Chat) fácil de usar desarrollado por KDE. Proporciona un fácil acceso a las redes estándar IRC como Libera, donde se pueden encontrar los canales IRC de KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Konversation KDEren IRC (Internet Relay Chat / Interneteko txandakako berriketa) bezero lagunkoi bat da. IRC sare estandarretara sarbide erraza ematen du, Libera-ra esaterako, non KDE IRC kanalak aurki daitezkeen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Konversation on KDE:n käyttäjäystävällinen IRC-asiakas (Internet Relay Chat), joka tarjoaa helpon pääsyn IRC-vakioverkkoihin kuten Liberaan, mistä löytyvät KDE:n IRC-kanavat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Konversation est un client IRC (Internet Relay Chat) convivial de KDE. Il fournit un accès facile aux réseaux IRC standards tels que Libera, où les canaux IRC de KDE se trouvent.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Konversation é un cliente fácil de usar de Internet Relay Chat (IRC) de KDE. Facilita acceder a redes IRC estándar como Libera, onde pode atopar as canles de IRC de KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="he">Konversation הוא לקוח Internet Relay Chat (IRC) ידידותי מבית KDE. הוא מספק גישה פשוטה לרשתות IRC כגון Libera, בה ניתן למצוא את ערוצי ה־IRC של KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hu">A Konversation a KDE felhasználóbarát Internet Relay Chat (IRC) kliense. Könnyű hozzáférést biztosít a szabványos IRC hálózatokhoz, mint például a Libera, ahol a KDE IRC csatornák találhatók.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Konversation adalah klien Internet Relay Chat (IRC) yang mudah digunakan oleh KDE. Ini menyediakan akses mudah ke jaringan IRC standar seperti Libera, di mana saluran IRC KDE bisa ditemukan.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Konversation è un client per Internet Relay Chat (IRC) facile da usare sviluppato da KDE. Fornisce un acceso rapido alle reti IRC standard come Libera, dove si possono trovare i canali IRC di KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">Konversation მეგობრული IRC-ის კლიენტია KDE-სგან. ის წარმოგიდგენთ ადვილ წვდომას სტანდარტულ IRC ქსელებთან, როგორიცაა, მაგალითად, Libera, სადაც KDE-ის IRC არხებია განთავსებული.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">Konversaion은 KDE의 IRC 클라이언트입니다. KDE IRC 채널이 있는 Libera와 같은 IRC 네트워크에 쉽게 연결할 수 있습니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="lv">„Konversation“ ir KDE izstrādāts lietotājiem draudzīgs internetā retranslētas tērzēšanas (IRC) klients. Tas nodrošina vieglu piekļuvi standarta IRC tīkliem, piemēram, „Libera“, kurā atrodami KDE IRC kanāli.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Konversation is een gebruikersvriendelijke Internet Relay Chat (IRC)-client door KDE. Het biedt gemakkelijk toegang tot standaard IRC-netwerken zoals Libera, waar de KDE IRC-kanalen zijn te vinden.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nn">Konversation er eit brukarvennleg prateprogram for IRC (Internet Relay Chat) frå KDE. Det gjev enkel tilgang til IRC-nettverk som Libera, der du finn IRC-kanalen for KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Konversation jest przyjaznym użytkownikowi programem do obsługi Internet Relay Chat (IRC) dla KDE. Zapewnia łatwy dostęp do standardowych sieci IRC, takich jak Libera, na których można znaleźć kanały IRC dla KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Konversation é um cliente amigável de Internet Relay Chat (IRC) do KDE. Oferece um acesso rápido às redes-padrão de IRC, como o Libera - onde se encontram os canais de IRC do KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Konversation é um cliente de IRC (Internet Relay Chat) amigável do KDE. Ele fornece acesso fácil a redes IRC padrão, como Libera, onde os canais IRC do KDE podem ser encontrados.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Konversation — клиент IRC с дружественным интерфейсом, разработанный KDE. Он обеспечивает доступ к стандартным сетям IRC (например, к Libera), где находятся IRC-каналы KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sa">Konversation KDE द्वारा उपयोक्तृ-अनुकूलः Internet Relay Chat (IRC) क्लायन्ट् अस्ति । एतत् Libera इत्यादिषु मानक IRC संजालेषु सुलभं प्रवेशं प्रदाति, यत्र KDE IRC चैनल्स् द्रष्टुं शक्यन्ते ।</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Konversation je používateľsky priateľský klient pre IRC od KDE. Poskytuje ľahký prístup ku štandardným IRC sieťam ako Libera, KDE sa dajú nájsť KDE IRC kanály.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Konversation je uporabniku prijazen odjemalec Internet Relay Chat (IRC), ki ga izdelal KDE. To omogoča enostaven dostop do standardnih omrežij IRC, kot je Libera, kjer najdete lahko IRC kanale za KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Konversation är en användarvänlig IRC-klient (Internet Relay Chat) av KDE. Det erbjuder enkel åtkomst till vanliga IRC-nätverk såsom Libera, där KDE:s IRC-kanal finns.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Konversation, KDE tarafından yapılan, kullanıcı dostu bir IRC istemcisidir. KDE IRC kanallarının bulunduğu Libera gibi standart IRC ağlarına kolay erişim sağlar.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Konversation — зручний для користування клієнт Internet Relay Chat (IRC) від KDE. Програма надає простий доступ до стандартних мереж IRC, зокрема Libera, де можна знайти канали IRC KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">Konversation 是一个由 KDE 团队打造的、便于使用的 Internet Relay Chat (IRC) 客户端。它可轻松访问如 Libera 在内的标准 IRC 网络，也能在此找到 KDE 的 IRC 频道。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">Konversation 是一個來自 KDE 的友善 IRC 用戶端。它讓存取標準 IRC 網路變得簡單，包含 KDE 的 IRC 頻道所在的 Libera。</p>
    <p>Konversation supports popular platforms like Linux, Windows and FreeBSD. It is the default IRC client in many prominent Linux distributions, such as openSUSE, the KDE spin of Fedora, and Kubuntu.</p>
    <p>IRC users can share files with other online users. Direct Client-to-Client (DCC) is a type of peer-to-peer filesharing using an IRC server for handshaking in order to exchange files or perform non-relayed chats. A typical DCC session runs independently from the IRC server once established.</p>
    <p>Konversation has one of the best user interfaces among all other IRC clients. The UI is very user friendly and easy for a beginner to use. At the same time, Konversation is highly configurable. Create command aliases, change the default, choose the default tabs position, and a lot more are available in the options.</p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image width="1920" height="1048">https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/konversation/konversation.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://konversation.kde.org/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=konversation</url>
  <url type="help">https://docs.kde.org/?application=konversation</url>
  <url type="donation">https://www.kde.org/community/donations/?app=konversation&amp;source=appdata</url>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>konversation</binary>
  </provides>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.10.25082" date="2025-10-09"/>
    <release version="1.10.25081" date="2025-09-11"/>
    <release version="1.10.25080" date="2025-08-14"/>
    <release version="1.10.25043" date="2025-07-03"/>
    <release version="1.10.25042" date="2025-06-05"/>
    <release version="1.10.25041" date="2025-05-08"/>
    <release version="1.10.25040" date="2025-04-17"/>
    <release version="1.10.24123" date="2025-03-06"/>
    <release version="1.10.24122" date="2025-02-06"/>
    <release version="1.10.24121" date="2025-01-09"/>
    <release version="1.10.24120" date="2024-12-12"/>
    <release version="1.10.24083" date="2024-11-07"/>
    <release version="1.10.24082" date="2024-10-10"/>
    <release version="1.10.24081" date="2024-09-12"/>
    <release version="1.10.24080" date="2024-08-22"/>
    <release version="1.10.24052" date="2024-07-04"/>
    <release version="1.10.24051" date="2024-06-13"/>
    <release version="1.10.24050" date="2024-05-23"/>
    <release version="1.10.24022" date="2024-04-11"/>
    <release version="1.10.24021" date="2024-03-21"/>
    <release version="1.10.24020" date="2024-02-28"/>
    <release version="1.9.23085" date="2024-02-15"/>
  </releases>
  <custom>
    <value key="KDE::irc">#konversation</value>
    <value key="KDE::mailinglist-devel">konversation-devel@kde.org</value>
    <value key="KDE::forum">18</value>
  </custom>
  <update_contact>konversation-devel@kde.org</update_contact>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
